[RAZOR BUZZING]
[HUMMING]
Ahh!
Hmm!
- I suppose we could
just fire him.
[LAUGHING, AGREEING]
[CERAMIC SHATTERING]
[SIGHS]
[SWISHING]
Of course, we'll have to
give him three month's notice.
- Yes...
- Subtle nonsense.
Leave it to me.
I'll talk to the chairman and insist
on Mr Bean's immediate dismissal.
- [LAUGHING, AGREEING]
- Well then, back to the agenda.
- The Grierson Gallery of California has
recently received a private donation
of fifty million dollars to spend on
buying Whistler's portrait of his mother
- from the Muse D'Orsay in Paris.
- It is quite simply, the most historic
purchase made by an American gallery
- this century.
- [CROWD] George! George!
- It's as simple as this.
The greatest painting ever by an American
artist is returning, at last, to America.
From now on, Whistler's Mother lives right
here in Los Angeles where she belongs!
When will we
actually see her?
The unveiling will be in about
two weeks, and you're all invited.
- [CROWD] George!
Hey! George!
They've asked us to send a scholar
of great weight in substance,
to preside over the ceremony and
stay on for a couple of months
- of lectures and seminars.
- Dr Rosenblum... Dr Cutler...
You both hold high claim
on this... great honor.
- Chairman's here, sir.
- Excellent. Send him in.
Oh, and run and fetch
Mr Bean, will you?
We are about
to fire him.
- Marvelous!
- Yes.
- Mr Bean is the worst employee
in the gallery's history.
[SNORING]
[CHAIR TAPS FLOOR]
[SNORING, GROANING]
[THUMP]
[SNORING]
Good afternoon, sir.
Sit down, sit down.
Now, before we move on to
the major business of the day,
I should like to approach
the question of Mr Bean.
Now, Mr Bean has worked
for us for many years.
- And will for
many years to come.
- I employed this splendid young
man when I was doing your job, Charles.
And you can have my resignation
if you go anywhere near him.
Ah.
[BLOWS NOSE]
[BLOWS NOSE VIOLENTLY]
[CONTINUES BLOWING NOSE]
Ah!
Hmm!
He's a fine, young fellow.
Absolutely. Quite right.
- V- very well. Moving on.
Um...
The Grierson Gallery of California needs
a representative of our great gallery.
- They are looking for a scholar
of a very high standard.
I have therefore decided
to recommend the post
and the three month's sabbatical that
goes with it, that splendid employee...
Mr Bean!
[LAUGHING]
- Yes!
- All those in favor?
[ALL] Yeah!
- Excellent! Carried.
- Our loss... is
America's gain.
[CLEARS THROAT]
David.
I got a letter from the
Royal National Gallery.
- They're recommending a guy
called "Bean" to represent them.
Bean? I can't say
I've heard of him.
Well, the letter's signed by
Doctors Rosenblum and Cutler.
- Well that's impressive.
- [CHUCKLES] Yeah.
They say he's a man whose "incontrovertible
genius dwarfs our own meager talents."
- Rosenblum and
Cutler said that?
Well, you asked for England's top
man. I do believe I delivered him.
Yes, it certainly
sounds like it!
- Uh--
- However,
Before we confirm, Bernice here still
feels that we'd get more media attention
if we have someone from, let's
say, the entertainment industry.
I genuinely believe that we
could get Jon Bon Jovi.
- Jon Bon Jovi?
- Mmm.
- To unveil Whister's Mother?
- Yes.
I have nothing
against Jon Bon Jovi.
The man has had two great
hairstyles in the last ten years,
which is an achievement
not to be sniffed at,
but so far as I know, Mr Jovi
knows absolutely nothing about
nineteenth century
impressionism.
Certainly hasn't mentioned it
in any of his recent songs.
- No, but David--
- This is not a rock video.
This is a great and
serious work of art.
And Dr Bean will give the
occasion depth and dignity.
[CAMERA SHUTTERS]
You're right.
We go with Bean.
- George--
- No, no, no, no.
David's our curator.
This is David's call.
It's his decision, his responsibility,
and ultimately, his neck.
[CAMERA SHUTTERS]
And where do you
want him to stay?
I have a rather
interesting idea...
Here?
In our house?
For two months?
[CHUCKLING]
Whoa, David,
what, suddenly there's no
hotels in Los Angeles?
Hey, there's no need to get excited,
here. I just thought, you know,
this is the Royal National
Gallery of England's top man.
I thought it'd be very exciting
to have around, to learn from,
- Mm-hmm.
- and talk to--
So do we know anything
about our new best friend?
- No, I think they might have mentioned it
if he was a notorious serial killer.
Are you feeling
lucky, punk?
[CAMERA SHUTTERS]
- David, you know, we have
an expression in this country.
It says "over my
dead body."
- Ally...
- I'd like to put it on the table,
- right here and now.
- Look, look, look...
This is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
- And it could be seriously
great for the kids.
You're kidding.
- Come on!
It's gonna be great.
- Let's say there is a chart
of the most intelligent people
you've ever met in your life. Well at
number one with a bullet is Dr Bean.
- Kevin, you know sometimes you
ask me questions that I can't answer.
Like "What is an
intrauterine device?"
[STUTTERING] Well I think more
like, "What's the meaning of life?"
- I never asked you that.
- It's fine. It- it doesn't matter.
[CHUCKLING] What I am saying, here,
is that Dr Bean is a very remarkable man.
- [SCOFFS]
- Hey, hey, for all you know,
he could be
very cute!
[HEAVENLY MUSIC]
Oh come on, the guy
is gonna be a creep.
All English men are ugly. I just
look at Prince Charles and weep.
- Okay, so he's gonna
look like Meat Loaf's butt.
Yeah, and that's
if we get lucky.
- Jennifer, no one is
asking you to marry him.
- You know, I don't know why
we have these family conferences
if dad's already
made up his mind.
- Perceptive child.
- Hey, what's wrong with Meat Loaf's butt?
Oh, come on, everybody!
It's gonna be great.
Dr Bean is a genius of
the very highest order.
Good evening.
[CAMERA SHUTTERS]
[CHUCKLING]
Uh, no, sir. You're
in first class.
Good evening.
[CHUCKLES HAPPILY]
[MOCKING PASSENGERS]
Good evening, sir.
may I take your coat?
- Oh! [GRUNTS IN APPROVAL]
- Thank you.
[CHUCKLES]
[YAWNS]
[AUDIBLY SIGHS]
[CHUCKLES, SNORTS]
[EXCLAIMS HAPPILY]
[CAMERA SHUTTERS]
[SNORTS]
- Good. Simple poster.
Nice and big.
It's actual size.
A bargain at 9.99.
- Spencer.
- Yes.
Bath towel.
- Mmm! Yeah. Pushing your
luck a little, here, Walter.
It'll sell.
- It's Whistler's sister.
- Oh, you are kidding.
No, sir. We have a range for
every member of the family.
Whistler's Mother's cookies.
Chocolate chip.
Whistler's father's beer mug.
[LID TAPPING]
And here's a really cute one
for the younger brother range.
- Whistler's whistle.
- Yeah...
- You just blow up her ass. Here, try.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, I get it.
[SIGHS]
- Mommy, I don't feel well.
[GULP]
- I'm gonna be sick.
[VOMITING]
Ah!
[LOUD, GOOEY POP]
- [INTERCOM] Your attention, please.
- Here, sir.
-Welcome to Los Angeles
International Airport.
- Do not leave baggage or
other items unattended.
[MAN] Hey!
Any second, now.
Think we're looking for
a Brad Pitt look-alike.
- Police!
- [CROWD SCREAMING]
- Move on him, now! Move it!
- Take it easy.
- Watch it! Watch it!
- Everyone outta the way!
In pursuit of a 415! A man with a gun
heading into Zone 10, terminal 2.
Get some people
over here, now!
- Get outta the way,
get outta the way!
- Move it! Move!
Move! Move!
- [GASPING]
- Police! Coming through!
- Come on, lady,
watch it! Move!
- [PANICKED GASPING]
- There he is! There he is!
- Move! Move! Move!
- Police! Everyone on
the floor, now!
[CROWD SCREAMING]
- Not you, sweetie.
- Oh, right!
[GUNS COCKING]
Carefully take
out your weapon,
- holding the butt
with two fingers only!
- Slowly place
it on the floor,
- and take three steps back.
[SHAKY BREATHING]
[GULPS]
- [WHISPERING] What is this?
- I don't know. Weird.
- [SIGHS]
- Mr Bean,
are you presently on
any kind of medication?
Not that I know of.
Well, you can
certainly use some.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
- So, Doctor...
- Uh, Bean...
Yes, okay, Dr Bean.
- Uh- uh [STUTTERS]
- Well, you- you made it.
- Nice flight?
- [MUMBLING]
[CHUCKLES]
- Well, this is Kevin.
- Ah.
- And this is Jennifer. She's been
very excited about meeting you.
- My wife, Alison.
David, can I just have the tiniest
talk with you in the kitchen?
- All right, yeah.
I'm just gonna--
I appreciate that on first viewing,
he seems a little eccentric.
David, there are martians who have been
exiled from Mars for looking weird
who look less weird
than this guy.
- He has an original quality.
- He goes today.
[FOCUSED GRUNTS]
- Wow, that was amazing!
- That's really cool!
Hey, can you do this?
[PLEASED GRUNT]
No. But I can do this.
- Neat! Wow! How
do you do that?
Magic. [SNORTS]
-So you're gonna tell him?
- Yes.
- Today? Okay.
- Yes, today, today, today.
- Today seems like a good day.
- Good.
Hmm!
[DOOR CLATTERING]
- Well, sir, an unorthodox start.
[CHUCKLES]
I guess I never expected things with
a man of your caliber to- to be normal.
- I- I gotta confess, I've never actually
read anything you've written.
- Uh, tell me, Doctor, what exactly
is your position at the gallery?
I sit in the corner...
and look at the paintings.
[EXCLAIMS]
That is brilliant!
- If only more scholars would
do that, you know, just sit and look.
- You know, not lecturing,
write and argue.
Just sit and look at the
paintings themselves.
Now that is brilliant. Yep.
Yes.
- Morning, Elmer.
- Good morning, sir.
- Dr Bean?
- Oh.
- Would you like
to sign in, sir?
Thank you. Welcome to
the Grierson, Dr Bean.
Welcome to my world.
We're expected in Grierson's
office in 9am, now this is a man
who does not like to be
kept waiting, so if you--
- Do you mind if I--
- Oh, yeah, okay, absolutely.
You bet.
All right.
[ZIPS PANTS]
[SIGHS CONTENTLY]
[HUMMING HAPPILY]
[EXCLAIMS]
- [GASPING]
[DRYER HUMS]
[GASPS]
[HOPPING GRUNTS]
[SIGHING HAPPILY]
Hi.
[HMM-ING]
[GASPING IN PAIN]
[BULB SHATTERS]
[EXCLAIMS]
Doctor? We should make a
move. We're very late.
[GASPING IN PAIN]
[EXCLAIMS]
Oh! we-- you--
Doctor... [STUTTERS]
When you're ready.
Okay.
- Ah, David, finally.
And this must be our
professor from across the sea.
Yes. George Grierson,
this is Dr Bean.
I'm delighted, Doctor.
- Actually, I'm no--
- Dr Bean! Can we get a photo, please?
[CAMERA SHUTTERS]
Right there.
We've heard a great deal
about you, Doctor.
[WHISPERING] We expect
a great deal of you.
- And this is Bernice,
in charge of PR.
- An absolute honor, Doctor.
- all right, thank you.
And Walter Huntley,
our merchandise manager.
- Nice to meet you...
- Moving along. Take a seat, Doctor.
- Here, let me take that old thing.
- [EXCLAIMS]
This is very out of date.
- Thank you.
- Before we settle in, you might
want to feast your eyes on these.
Oh--
[CHUCKLES]
Well, I'll be honest
with you, Bean.
- I like this.
- It's beautiful, sir.
- It is. Yeah.
- Mmm!
- Over here.
- Okay.
Lovely green...
- Good, good. Down to business.
- Okay...
- I've asked Bernice to run through
the order of events for the opening of...
Dr Bean, would you
like to join us?
[MUTTERING]
Uh, no-- no, I'll-
- Very well...
Bernice.
Now, you will know that anything
pertaining to special media requirements
- is prefixed with an asterisk,
- Mm-hmm.
- i.e., glossy stills requested by some
of the favored weeklies. That sort of thing.
- Right. So, the big day
unfolds as follows:
- Our generous benefactor,
General Newton, will be
arriving at 10am to meet
the members of the staff.
- Then at 10:30, we'll have
the unveiling of the picture.
- Now, this will be in front
of all press and media.
Walter, I'm assuming all this merchandising
is gonna be made available.
Oh, absolutely. From fridge magnets
to frizbees, we'll be ready.
- So it will probably be at about 11am
when the stage is set for Dr Bean.
- [MOANING]
- Yes. I really...
really should bring in
the Doctor, here.
[MOANING]
Uh, Dr Bean?
[ GRUNTS IN CONTENT]
- Doctor, we've just been
inspecting this schedule.
and--
If you would just like to take a look
at yours over there at your convenience...
Uh, the General should
be arriving at 10am,
- and he'll unveil the
picture at 10:30.
So at about 11:00 we should
be, um, ready for your speech.
- Yes, and uh, I think...
twenty minutes should...
should be long enough.
- Don't you, Bernice?
- Absolutely.
I know you could fill hours,
Doctor, but for thew press,
- it would be best if you
could keep it quite light.
Maybe throw in some anecdotes
about actual painting of the picture,
uh, and explain why it is considered
to be America's greatest painting.
- [EXCLAIMS QUIETLY]
- Is that going to be enough, Doctor?
Twenty minutes?
[MUTTERS]
Well, dear friends, if you'll excuse
me, I have a lunch with the Mayor.
Not the kind of thing
I like, but duty calls.
Well, Doctor, it's
good to meet you.
It's a complex experience.
Enjoy your stay with David.
They're simple people but warm.
- David, if I may have just a private word?
- Okay. Uh...
I tell you, why don't you wait for
me back at the new acquisitions.
I'll join you shortly. Yeah.
- He's a genius, right?
- Yeah, he's eccentric, but...
- Yes.
- Yeah.
The unveiling of Whistler's Mother
is the most important thing
to ever happen to this gallery,
and Dr Bean was your choice.
Yes, I understand that.
Thank you, sir.
Dr Bean, when we
get home, I wonder--
[SIGHS]
When we get home, I wonder if you would
mind giving me a private moment with my wife.
There's a little something
we need to work out.
No problem.
[MIXER WHIRRING]
Yeah, I think, uh... Just wait
in here would be good.
Oh, just ignore that.
Her mother gave it to us.
- Huge sentimental
value, you know, so...
- Just make yourself at home. I'll be
just a couple of minutes with Alison.
- Oh! Doctor, I would
actually not do that.
- That's... that's a limited edition.
It's that it's delicate, so if you...
- Or, yeah, if... Put it there
would be good. Yeah.
Okay, that's... All right.
[MIXER WHIRRING]
- Hi.
- Hi!
- No Dr Bean?
- Well actually, no, he is still here,
- but let me-- I just want us to--
- Jennifer! Kevin!
- Plan B!
- What is-- You have luggage packed?
- What is Plan B?
- Plan B is,
if you haven't gotten rid of Dr Bean,
we go straight to Grandma's.
- I can't believe you--
- Screwed up again, huh, Dad?
Oh, come on! There was no
time to raise the subject!
- Kevin, start the car, would you, sweetie?
- Oh, Ali, wait a second and look.
No, you look, David, my darling.
I have asked very little from you,
but I did ask you to get rid of Dr Bean,
and you have made your choice,
so you two can stay here and really
come to grips with postmodernism,
but I am taking our
children to my mother's.
Just give him one last chance.
- Oh, David...
- Just one.
Please?
Okay.
- Okay. All right.
- Thank you. Thanks.
Once you get to know him,
- I think you're gonna--
- David, don't.
- Hello, Doctor.
- Hello.
[BEEPING]
- No, no, no, no, Doctor, that
is not for the TV. That's for the...
[ALISON GASPING]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
Yeah.
Well.
There they go.
Well, Doctor, we've got
the whole weekend together.
Yeah, get to know
each other and, uh...
I was thinking tomorrow
we might really do LA.
Uh, there's the Gallery of American Indian
Art. There's the California State Gallery.
There's actually this new place, the Rabowitz,
which is kind of the place for abstract expressionism.
Does that, uh... Does
that sound good to you?
- Maybe you have
something else in mind?
♪ Round, round, get around,
I get around, yeah ♪
♪ Get around, round, round,
I get around ♪
♪ I get around,
from town to town ♪
♪ I'm a real cool head ♪
♪ I'm making real good bread ♪
♪ I'm getting bugged driving
up and down the same old strip ♪
♪ I gotta find a new place
where the kids are hip ♪
♪ My buddies and me
are getting real well-known... ♪
[EXCLAIMING]
[BORED SIGHING]
[ALL LAUGHING]
[LAUGHING]
Oh!
[SNORING]
Incredible.
- You set?
- [STARTLED GRUNT]
Why don't you get another ticket?
Could be more fun second time round.
Okay.
Brace yourself.
[ALL SCREAMING]
[WOMAN YELLS]
[SCREAMING]
[MAN YELLS]
[SIGHS]
[EXCLAIMS]
- He's a genius, huh?
- That's what they tell me.
Well, he looks like
a fruitcake to me.
Willing to take
responsibility for his actions?
- [EXCLAIMS]
- [GASPS]
Well, you're a braver
man than me,
and I single-handedly take
on gangs armed with AK-47s.
Get him out of here. Tell him his is
a butt I would dearly love to kick,
and the next time, I will.
Doctor, there is something
we have to talk about,
- and I don't quite
know how to put this...
- [HUMMING]
- What I am concerned about, is--
- [DOORBELL RINGS]
Whoever that is, I am
getting rid of them.
There he is!
David. Sorry we're late.
[AIR KISSING]
- The traffic! Oh, terrible.
- Oh, that's beautiful!
- Every day, it gets
worse and worse.
- It's just the way she... It's the green.
- And why? Because nobody's in control.
No, it's the yellow! It's just...
It's the yellow. She is a...
- Well, where is Alison?
- Well, uh,
I've got some bad news
and some good news.
The bad news is that Alison
has had to go visit her mom,
who, well, is not well.
- That's too bad.
- Gee, the poor thing.
- Sorry to hear that, David.
- The good news,
is that Dr Bean and
I will be cooking.
- Oh! [LAUGHING]
- You sure that's good news?
Well, of course it is!
- All the greatest chefs
in the world are men.
So what's on the
menu, maestro?
How could I forget?
What the hell are we
going to give them?
Yes, I think they may be expecting
something slightly more formal.
- An onion? Just on its own?
No, no, don't be ridiculous. That's for
Thanksgiving, and Alison would kill me.
No, no. There must
be something else.
- Have you ever cooked one of these before?
- Oh, yes.
But it- it would take
like five hours, right?
Not necessarily...
[GRUNTING]
What do you think?
Twenty minutes?
I- I don't know.
- You're sure this is gonna work?
- [MUTTERING]
Okay, you're the chef. Just put on some
vegetables and come and say hello.
Oh! Maestro.
- My taste buds are positively
tingling with anticipation.
No. No, thanks.
- I think we'll pass
on the appetizer.
So, Bean...
Big day, Tuesday. Your
big day, my big day.
I have a question for you.
[MICROWAVE BEEPING]
- He's very, uh,
attentive to detail.
- Everything must be just so.
[LOUD EXPLOSION]
- Bean, I think we need to
be honest with each other.
I cannot deny that,
over the last days,
some suspicions have begun
to gather in my mind,
and I would just like to ask
you some direct questions.
- Okay?
Number one...
Are you a doctor?
No.
Number two...
- Do you know
anything about art?
Um...
Well...
Just for instance here, um...
[CHUCKLES]
Was Leonardo da Vinci an
American basketball player?
[LAUGHS]
Yes.
- Hi, Dad.
Hello, Doctor.
- Bye, Dad.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SIGHING]
♪ Yesterday ♪
♪ All my troubles
seemed so far away ♪
♪ Now it looks as though
they're here to stay ♪
- ♪ Oh, I believe in yesterday ♪
- Yep.
♪ Suddenly ♪
♪ I'm not half the
man I used to be ♪
♪ There's a shadow
hanging over me ♪
♪ Oh, yesterday
came suddenly ♪
♪ Why she
had to go ♪
♪ I don't know,
she wouldn't say ♪
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTS]
For God's sake, Bean,
what are you doing?
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello?
Mr Grierson, yes. He's just
here in the shower with me.
Would you give me--
Yes, hello, Mr Grierson.
Oh no, no, you must have
misunderstood him. What can I--
She is? Oh, thank
you for calling me.
- Yes, okay. Goodbye.
- Bye!
I can't believe it. Whistler's Mother
has actually arrived in America.
Now, listen,
I am begging you,
as a man whose entire
professional career depends on you,
behave rationally today.
There is no God.
What do you think?
Nice frame.
She's magnificent.
David, well done. Worth
every bright green buck!
She's something else, isn't she?
All right, folks. Enjoy her while you can.
After this morning, we lock her away
until the guy who paid
$50 million for her turns up.
[LAUGHING]
And, Elmer, I believe we
have a security meeting.
That's right, sir.
And, ah!-- This is your key
to the encasement system.
There are only two.
I have the other one.
So, if the painting turns up
missing, I'll know where to come.
[LAUGHING]
And if you could all join
me at the security console?
Doctor, why don't
you just stay here?
Maybe a look at the real thing
will inspire you for your speech.
Just stay here. Don't leave
this room till I get back, okay?
[SIGHING]
This chart maps all the
security elements for the big day.
And as usual in these circumstances,
I've given the operation a code name,
which is Operation
Whistler's Mother.
It's not a snazzy title,
but I think it works.
[TAPPING]
Tss!
[BLOWING]
Aah... aah... aah... aah...
[SIGHING]
[SNEEZES]
Ugh...
[PANICKED STUTTERING]
[EXCLAIMS]
[GASPING]
Fear not, gentlemen.
With the system we put in here,
nothing will touch that painting
short of an earthquake that
brings down the whole gallery.
[GRUNTING]
[HOCKING]
[EXCLAIMING]
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
[GRUNTING]
[FAKE SQUEAKING SOUNDS]
[REAL SQUEAKING SOUNDS]
Ooh!
[FAKE SQUEAKING SOUNDS]
Once we've gotten
the general safely inside,
the key figure,
security-wise, will be Dr Bean.
- We gotta protect the painting without
getting in the good doctor's way.
Ah.
[SIGHS IN RELIEF]
[CANS TUMBLING]
[EXCLAIMS]
[PANICKED STUTTERING]
[WHIMPERING]
[EXCLAIMING]
[KNOCKING]
There seems to be
a problem with the...
[PANICKED STUTTERING]
door...
Where's the picture gone?
Um...
[STUTTERING]
What? what, what, what?
Oh, Jesus! Oh, God!
Oh- Oh, Jesus!
- God! Oh, Mary, mother of
Jesus! Jesus of Nazareth!
Wait a minute. Why am I
worrying about this? You did it!
- All I have to do is go out and
tell them what happened!
No, perfect!
Then they'll say, "Well, who left
him alone with the picture?"
And I say, "Me." Then they say,
"Well, you're fired!" I say, "Fine."
No, no, no, no, no! Then they say,
"Firing is not enough."
- "Let's prosecute you
for negligence!"
Then I go to jail. My wife leaves me.
My daughter becomes a prostitute.
I wind up on death row, sharing
a cell with Butch McDick!
- All right, calm down.
I just gotta calm down.
Okay. Okay.
Give me one more
look at the painting.
- Oh, God! Oh, God!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
...which renders the underground
ventilation ducts completely secure.
- Yes, well, that's good to know.
- Thank you, sir.
Hey, do you drink, Bean?
- No.
- Good. Neither do I.
[TV] Yeah, this one has extra
innings written all over it, doesn't it?
All right, he hands
over the plate.
He's got the long-ball
threat from the left side.
Smith corks one to
right field down the line.
- There it goes.
- Bean?
It's going!
[CHEERING]
Going crazy, folks!
Going crazy! It's a home run!
And the Cardinals
have won the...
[BLEATING]
Carry on.
You wanna know what the
reality of the situation is?
Okay, this is it.
Because you moved into my
house, my wife has moved out.
Yes, she did. She might have moved
out anyway, but that is one- point one.
Point two,
I've given my life to art,
and from here on in,
the only art I will get anywhere near
are the pictures I draw on the pavement,
hoping passers-by will
throw nickels in my hat.
I guess the long
and the short of it,
I wish I'd never been born.
- Yesterday...
all my troubles
seemed so far away...
Now it looks as though
they're here to stay.
I believe...
in yesterday.
Suddenly!
- I'm not half the man I used to be!
- Oh, no.
There's a shadow
hanging over me.
I believe in yesterday.
- Suddenly!
- Mmm...
- [BOTH] Row, row, row, your boat,
gently down the stream,
[BOTH] If you see a crocodile,
don't forget to scream!
- Ah!
- Splish, splash, splish, splash.
[BOTH] Row, row, row your boat,
gently down the stream,
If you see a crocodile,
don't forget to scream!
[SCREAMING]
[SIGHS]
- I can explain everything.
- Okay, explain everything.
- It's inexplicable. Ali, listen--
- David, no.
David, the reason that I
came home was because
I missed you. And also because
I live here. And they live here.
- but, David, we have been waiting
for five hours, and what do we get?
A drunk, and his friend
from the planet Zog!
- I know, and it seems like this
horrible situation, but if you could...
If you could just hear
my full horrific tale...
David, I think I'm
gonna have to leave you.
You are?
Well, then things really
have gotten bad.
Yeah.
- Hi, Beanie.
Can't sleep, huh?
No.
Me, neither.
Can't stop thinking
about naked women.
- What about you?
- Whistler's Mother.
Well, whatever turns you on.
Catch you around, moon-man.
Oh, if you still can't
sleep, come to my room.
I got some great posters of
Cindy Crawford on my wall.
[EXCLAIMING]
[GROANING]
Come on!
[LOUD BANGING]
[GROANING]
- [GUARD SCREAMING]
[THUD]
[GRUNTS]
[GROANING]
[SIGHING IN RELIEF]
Hooray!
[PANG]
Ah!
Oh, my God!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[ENGINE RUMBLING]
Jennifer!
No, no, no, no, no! Don't think for one
minute you're getting on that bike, Jen.
Morning, everyone.
[STRETCHES]
- Total family rule, here. No one
is allowed on one of those death traps.
- You promised me, Jen.
- You promised mom you'd get rid of Dr Freako!
[ENGINE ROARING]
[CHUCKLES]
- Um--
- Don't talk to me.
I am trying to think
what I'm going to do.
- Well...
- Quiet!
- There they are!
- What a pleasure, sir.
Welcome to our humble abode.
Not too humble, I hope.
I'm expecting lunch.
- Of course. General, right this way.
- After you, sir. After you.
[REPORTERS CHATTERING]
Glad you could make it.
- Where the hell have you been?
- I am sorry. Trouble at home.
- Never mind. Come along.
- Sir, there is something...
General, I'd like you to meet
our curator, David Langley.
- I'm delighted to meet you, sir.
- Of course you are.
Right through here, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is
a great moment for America.
And for one very special
lady, Whistler's Mother.
[CLAPPING]
- And she's here today, thanks
to our great and good benefactor.
Will you join me in saluting a
soldier, philanthropist, loving father...
and an extremely generous patron
of the arts, General Newton?
[CLAPPING]
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
I am not a traditional art lover.
I don't know the difference
between a Picasso and a car crash.
- But I love my country.
I can't stand the idea of a bunch of Frenchies
owning America's greatest painting.
Let's get on with it.
Welcome home, Ma.
[CHEERING, CLAPPING]
Whatever you did, you're
a genius, and I love you!
It's a poster.
It's a what?
- David, it's time.
- Uh, t- time for what?
- The speech.
- Wha-- I, Wait, what speech?
- Congratulations, David!
Dr Bean's speech
about the painting.
Yes, of course, the speech.
- Now, Doctor, try to
keep it below an hour,
and if there could be one
joke in it, that would be nice.
Good Morning America couldn't give
a flying monkey about "isms" and, uh...
- Oh, you know what I mean.
- Yeah.
[PANICKED STUTTERING]
- lt doesn't have to go on for long. Just...
- Dr Bean?
- We're ready for you. Right this way.
- Just... Just... Just... Just... Just... Just... Just...
- And now, for the second
highlight of our day.
Dr Bean, a great English art scholar,
is here to speak for a few minutes,
not too long, Doctor, on the
subject of our new purchase.
Ladies and gentlemen, Dr Bean
of the National Gallery of England.
[CLAPPING]
...
[CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY]
Um... Uh...
- Well...
Hello. I'm Dr Bean,
apparently...
And- and my job,
is to sit and
look at paintings.
[CLAPPING]
- [MAN] Just him and the painting?
Um, So... Um,
what have I learned that
I can say about this painting?
Um...
Well... well, firstly,
it's quite big.
- which is excellent.
- Mm-hmm.
- Because if it was really small,
you know, microscopic,
then hardly anybody would be able to
see it, which would be a tremendous shame.
Um, secondly,
and I'm getting quite
near the end now of this...
analysis of this painting...
Secondly,
why was it worth
this man, here,
- spending 50 million of your
American dollars on this portrait?
- And, and, and the
answer is, um...
- Well, this picture is worth
such a lot of money because...
it's a picture...
of Whistler's mother.
- And as I've learned by
staying with my best friend,
- David Langley, and his family,
families are very important.
- and even though Mr Whistler
was perfectly aware...
that his mother was a hideous old bat who
looked like she had a cactus lodged up her backside,
- [CHUCKLING]
- he stuck with her.
And even took the time to
paint this amazing picture of her.
It's not just a painting.
It's a picture of
a mad old cow,
- who he thought the world
of, and that's marvelous.
- [MAN] Well said.
- [CROWD CHATTERING]
Well, that's what
I think, anyway.
[CLAPPING]
- Home and dry.
- Where did you put the original?
Uh...
- Mr Langley, may
I have a word?
- Stay here. Shut up.
- Mr Langley--
- Okay, I can explain everything.
- What can you explain?
- About the painting.
- Which painting?
- Whistler's Mother.
I'm afraid, Mr Langley, I'm here in my capacity
as a police officer, not as an art lover.
It's about your daughter. She's
been in a motorcycle accident.
[SIRENS WAILING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Damn! Request emergency
clearance for 809-Adam.
Shut up!
- 211 in progress. Suspect male.
Possibly armed. Request immediate backup.
Keep speeding! If you get
a ticket, I'll tear it up.
- Thanks.
- Hold it!
- Hey, easy, fella, easy.
Hold it, there. Right there.
Whoa! Easy!
Put it down. Put the gun down.
[GUNSHOT]
Hi, I need Jennifer Langley's room. She came
in at about 11:00, motorcycle accident.
- Out of the way, sir.
- [GRUNTS]
[GROANING]
She's on the fifth floor, east
wing. Just take the elevator up.
Oh!
Just...
All right.
[EXCLAIMING]
I am so--
Just--
Please, just stay
here and do nothing!
If you do nothing,
nothing can go wrong.
I've got to take care
of my family now.
The nurse says that it's
not a coma, that she's just...
She's just sort of
taking time out.
But we haven't seen a
doctor yet, so I don't...
- Dr Jacobson?
- Yes?
We need you urgently in OR 3.
- No can do. I'm due in number 4 at 1:00.
- Sir, it's urgent!
We have a ruptured
kidney and massive bleeding.
Okay.
Yes, it's urgent!
- What's happening?
- Surgeon's on his way up.
- At last, Dr... Bean.
- Hello, Doctor. We've
got a 45-year-old male,
- blood type B negative, brought in
by paramedics 10 minutes ago.
- He's got a penetrating
injury to the left chest.
- Gotta get him in there right now.
- No, no, no!
Come in, Doctor. It looks like
a bullet in the lower thorax.
It seems to have ruptured the lung, and
severe inner bleeding along the abdomen.
- Doctor, he's coming to.
- All right, give him a T-70.
- Got it.
...
- [CHUCKLES]
- [GRUNTS]
Shall I extend the incision, sir?
- We've taken it from the
breastbone to the diaphragm.
We may have to extend
further to get to the spleen.
[STUTTERING]
Sorry, sir. It's only
my first week.
[MUTTERING]
No, you're right, Doctor.
We should wait for the x-rays.
- Help! We are losing
this guy out here!
- For Jesus' sake, we need help!
- Go! Go! Go! Get in here!
Watch he doesn't go into
haemodynamic shock.
We'll be right back.
- Defibrillating!
- All right, charge the paddles to 200 watts.
Clear!
[SIGHING]
[EXCLAIMS]
[GROANS]
Ah!
What's that?
[CHUCKLES]
Jolly good. Clean it up.
Sorry to keep you waiting, sir.
Nice work in there, people.
Now back to the bleeding!
- Where's this blood coming from? We got to
clamp it off. Where the hell's that J-17?
- We need that J-17 in OR 4 right now!
- He's got major trauma.
There's too much blood.
I can't see a thing.
- More suction!
- Somebody check that line.
- Blood pressure's bottoming out.
- Hook me up with 12, will you? Now!
- His heart rate is dropping.
We're gonna lose him.
- How's the TMS?
- Come on, people! He's crashing on us.
- Damn! I'm not getting a reading.
- Where is this bullet?
- Come on, hold on to him!
- If we don't find it, he's a dead man.
- I am not gonna lose this guy!
Sir, sir, we're losing him!
I've got to get in there now.
Doctor, you can't just...
It's too dangerous!
Ah, ah, ah, ah!
My God!
[PANG]
- Incredible.
- Heart rate is stabilizing.
- Blood pressure's climbing back.
[CLAPPING]
[GAWKING]
Oh, Doctor. Thank God. My
daughter was in an accident.
No one's even taken a look at her yet. We're
desperate for some medical attention in here.
Would you mind?
[COUGHS]
Don't worry, honey. The
doctor will check her out.
Oh, thank God.
- Mr and Mrs Langley,
- any kind of damage to the brain
is a very sensitive thing to observe,
so maybe we should just step outside and
give the doctor a little room to work.
- The first nurse said we shouldn't think
of it as a coma but more like a deep sleep.
- Yes, that's sort of true.
- Could I ask you a question?
Jennifer?
Wakey, wakey, breakfast's ready.
- What time is it?
It's almost 2:00.
Can you turn the clock
back about 12 hours for me?
Sure.
[SCREAMS]
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
I don't know what
to say about Bean.
He's clearly a force-10
disaster area, but...
God help me, I like him.
Now, having said that,
there is no reason in the world why any of you
should ever have anything to do with him again.
[GRUNTING]
[FRUSTRATED SIGHING]
[MACHINE POWERING UP]
[SCREAMING]
[EXCLAIMING]
Mom? Dad? Anyone?
Oh, my God, Jennifer!
- Oh, honey. Sweetie.
- Honey! Oh, look at you.
- What happened?
- You had an accident, honey,
but everything is
gonna be okay.
- But what happened to Stingo?
- Just bruises, collar bone.
- He'll be fine, until I
get my hands on him.
- Hey, Doctor, where are you going?
- Where do you think you're going?
How can we ever say thank you?
No, you've made us so happy.
- Tell us, what can we do? We'll do anything.
- Anything.
Well, I suppose you could
let me stay another week....
Sunset Boulevard.
♪ Rollin' down to
the Imperial Highway ♪
♪ With a big nasty
redhead at my side ♪
♪ Santa Ana winds
blowing hot from the north ♪
♪ And we was
born to ride ♪
♪ Roll down the window,
put down the top ♪
♪ Crank up the
Beach Boys, baby ♪
♪ Don't let
the music stop ♪
♪ We're gonna
ride it 'til we ♪
♪ Just can't ride
it no more ♪
[TIRES SCREECHING]
♪ From the South Bay
to the Valley ♪
♪ From the West Side
to the East Side ♪
♪ Everybody's
very happy ♪
♪ 'Cause the sun is
shining all the time ♪
♪ Looks like another
perfect day ♪
♪ I love L.A. ♪
♪ We love it ♪
- [HORN HONKING]
- ♪ We love it! ♪
- Presents! Presents!
- Hey! What's this all about?
- This is heavy!
- Thank you.
- Oh, look, laxatives.
Yeah, a whole box of them.
Oh, hey! there they are!
- Eggs. Six of them!
Barbie!
- Thanks.
- What did you get there?
Ta-daa!
[LAUGHING]
Turn around, smile!
- Oh, look at you!
- Wonderful!
Oh, my!
- Give us a smile!
- Bye-bye!
- Bye!
Bye, Beanie!
- See ya!
- Farewell!
Well, Beanie...
it's been...
[CHUCKLES] surreal.
Uh.. I want you to know you
can come back and visit anytime.
In the fairly distant future.
[CHUCKLES]
[CHUCKLING]
I- I know it sounds insane,
but I'm really gonna miss you.
Okay.
[EXCLAIMS]
Oh!
Okay. Goodbye again.
[SIGHS, SNORTS]
[SNAPS FINGERS]
[BOYZONE'S "PICTURE
OF YOU" PLAYS]
[THOMAS JULES' "THAT
KINDA GUY" PLAYS]
[ALISHA'S ATTIC'S
"HE'S A REBEL" PLAYS]
Yes, I normally stay
'til the end as well.
Bye.
You can go now if you...
If you wish.
Bye.
Subtitles written by
NGNT